<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>leetcode on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/tags/leetcode/</link><description>Recent content in leetcode on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:21:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/tags/leetcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leetcode: Maximum Subarray</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:21:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</guid><description>Introduction The Maximum Subarray problem is a classic challenge in computer science and algorithm design. It provides a great exercise for understanding array manipulation, optimization techniques, and dynamic programming. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the problem statement, explore solution approaches, and analyze their efficiencies.
The Problem Link to question
Given an integer array nums, find the contiguous subarray (containing at least one number) that has the largest sum and return its sum.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 16:44:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</guid><description>Introduction In the bustling city of algorithms and code, even garbage collection becomes an intriguing problem. This blog post delves into the LeetCode problem titled &amp;ldquo;Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage.&amp;rdquo; The objective is to efficiently plan the collection of metal (&amp;lsquo;M&amp;rsquo;), paper (&amp;lsquo;P&amp;rsquo;), and glass (&amp;lsquo;G&amp;rsquo;) garbage spread across houses using three specialized trucks.
The Problem Link to question
You are provided with an array of strings, garbage, where each element represents the assortment of garbage at a particular house.</description></item></channel></rss>