<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/</link><description>Recent content on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handle Interactive Shell</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</guid><description>Introduction Connecting to a remote service using a python module paramiko has always been one of the well-known methods to handle such tasks. Executing commands and receving the data back from the connected server can be done at ease. The following code is a basic usage of paramiko to interact with the server.
import paramiko host = &amp;#39;127.0.0.1&amp;#39; # server host username = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; password = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; # Init SSH client client = paramiko.</description></item><item><title>Python Generators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</guid><description>Objectives In this short blog, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce Python Generators. After reading this blog, I do hope that you will understand
What Python generators are What generator function and generator expression are How to use them What are Python Generators? A special function in Python that returns a lazy iterator. It works similar to a list, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store all values in memory
Implementation So, why do we need to use generators instead of normal interators (e.</description></item><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Rock Paper Scissors Rock Paper Scissors is a game where two players simultaneously choose one of three options: rock, paper, or scissors. The player who wins the most games wins the game.
It is clear that the game is a pure chance game regarding statistics if players truly randomly choose their choices. However, it is not the case for human behaviour.
The study Social cycling and conditional responses in the Rock-Paper-Scissors game suggest that the game is not purely chance game, but rather a game that is dependent on human behaviour.</description></item><item><title>Sokrates AI Platform</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/12/sokrates-ai-platform/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 16:48:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/12/sokrates-ai-platform/</guid><description>Introduction Sokrates collects data related to the interaction of classroom teaching and teaching behaviors applied by pedagogy, and use AI to automatically generate professional teaching analysis reports (machine intelligence), combined with the opinions of experts and teachers (expert wisdom), and use visual charts. It serves as a summary reference for lesson observation discussions and teacher self-improvement. Assist teachers&amp;rsquo; professional growth through AI technology.
It has collected tens of thousands of excellent teaching plans and teaching examples, established the AI Smarter School exclusive channel, and provided a teacher professional development platform for the global smart teachers to watch, discuss and communicate with the public, to promote the spread of smarter education and accelerate the teacher professional development.</description></item><item><title>Daylify</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:28:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</guid><description>Introduction Daylify is an experimental web application that allows users to record their moods on a daily basis.
Inspiration I wanted to create an easy-to-use web application to practice my skills. Furthermore, I would like to evaluate myself to see how I grow as a person, and to examine the highlights of my journey.
This project uses Vue.js for the UI, and FastAPI for the API which are hosted separately.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 Vaccination Log</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 09:10:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</guid><description>On 18-Aug-2020, Taiwan finally opened its first appointment for locally-made vaccine MVC COVID-19. As this will be the very first rollout of the vaccine, there are still some doubts towards the safety of the vaccine. However, I am confident that the vaccine will be safe and effective; therefore I decided to register to receive my first dose on 23-Aug-2020.
I will keep updating this log as I receive more information before and after receiving my doses.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Copilot</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:12:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</guid><description>What is GitHub Copilot? GitHub-Copilot is basically a smart code autocomplete powered by Codex, the new AI system created by OpenAI. GitHub Copilot understands significantly more context than most code assistants. So, whether it&amp;rsquo;s in a docstring, comment, function name, or the code itself, GitHub Copilot uses the context you&amp;rsquo;ve provided and synthesizes code to match.
I received an invitation to test out GitHub Copilot during its technical preview a couple of weeks ago, and I have been using it on Visual Studio Code ever since.</description></item><item><title>Introducing FastAPI</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:36:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</guid><description>Introduction Developing APIs can be painful if we don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. As I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of Python, it is my first choice for development. It has a great number of frameworks and libraries supporting web development (e.g., Django, Flask, etc.). This time I would like to introduce a super-fast and easy-to-use framework which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for a couple of years now: FastAPI.
FastAPI FastAPI is a high-performace web framework for creating APIs with Python.</description></item><item><title>Unconventional Russian Roulette</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:57:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Unconventional Russian Roulette? Unconventional Russian Roulette introduces similarities as its origin Russian Roulette. The difference is that instead of using one bullet, it uses three bullets where they are loaded adjacently.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine this scenario:
Three bullets are loaded into the cylinder adjacently, Player A has taken a shot and survived. We, as Player B, need to decide whether to take a shot or not. For the sake of simplicity, the game ends this round and here are the conditions:</description></item><item><title>Scavenger</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/11/scavenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 13:45:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/11/scavenger/</guid><description>Introduction Scavenger is an experimental web scraping project as a service that simply offers an easy-to-use functionality to scrap a website and gather a specific piece of information as needed.
Features Web Scraping: It gets its hands dirty going out to endless space of World Wide Web to make sure that you get what you need Processing: Gliding through a scraped website to seek a piece of information as required Presenting: It manages and presents the result beautifully to make it easier to comprehend Inspiration One of the core ideas on developing this project was that I wanted to create a web app application and deliver it within tight schedules.</description></item></channel></rss>