<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/</link><description>Recent content on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 16:39:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ORoaming by Oppo</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 16:39:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world, maintaining connectivity while traveling abroad has evolved from a luxury to a necessity. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a business traveler, a globetrotter, or someone who frequently explores new destinations, the demand for dependable and cost-effective international roaming solutions has never been more essential. Enter ORoaming.
Ordinarily, travelers need to acquire additional local or travel SIM cards, invest in Pocket WiFi devices, and explore various connectivity options to stay connected abroad.</description></item><item><title>Farewell Book Depository</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/05/farewell-book-depository/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 14:54:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/05/farewell-book-depository/</guid><description>Book Depository, once a prominent online book seller based in the UK, captured the hearts of book lovers around the world. Renowned for its vast collection of affordably-priced books and its unique offering of free worldwide shipping, Book Depository served as a haven for readers seeking diverse literary treasures. Particularly for individuals residing in third world countries, where foreign language books often come with exorbitant price tags, Book Depository provided an invaluable platform for access to knowledge and imagination.</description></item><item><title>Engineering to Consulting</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/04/engineering-to-consulting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/04/engineering-to-consulting/</guid><description>In 2022, I faced a career crossroads when I received an offer to become a consultant in a private tech firm. While excited about the opportunity to try something new, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel apprehensive about leaving behind my comfortable role as a software engineer. Ultimately, I took a leap of faith and accepted the offer, eager to see where this new path would take me.
However, my excitement quickly turned to reality when I realized that being a consultant requires a different skill set than what I had previously honed as an engineer.</description></item><item><title>Handle Interactive Shell</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</guid><description>Introduction Connecting to a remote service using a python module paramiko has always been one of the well-known methods to handle such tasks. Executing commands and receiving the data from the connected server can be done quickly. The following code is a primary usage of paramiko to interact with the server.
import paramiko host = &amp;#39;127.0.0.1&amp;#39; # server host username = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; password = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; # Init SSH client client = paramiko.</description></item><item><title>Python Generators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</guid><description>Objectives In this short blog, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce Python Generators. After reading this blog, I do hope that you will understand
What Python generators are What generator function and generator expression are How to use them What are Python Generators? A special function in Python that returns a lazy iterator. It works similar to a list, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store all values in memory
Implementation So, why do we need to use generators instead of normal interators (e.</description></item><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Rock Paper Scissors Rock Paper Scissors is a game where two players simultaneously choose one of three options: rock, paper, or scissors. The player who wins the most games wins the game.
It is clear that the game is a pure chance game regarding statistics if players truly randomly choose their choices. However, it is not the case for human behaviour.
The study Social cycling and conditional responses in the Rock-Paper-Scissors game suggest that the game is not purely chance game, but rather a game that is dependent on human behaviour.</description></item><item><title>Sokrates AI Platform</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/12/sokrates-ai-platform/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 16:48:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/12/sokrates-ai-platform/</guid><description>Introduction Sokrates collects data related to the interaction of classroom teaching and teaching behaviors applied by pedagogy, and use AI to automatically generate professional teaching analysis reports (machine intelligence), combined with the opinions of experts and teachers (expert wisdom), and use visual charts. It serves as a summary reference for lesson observation discussions and teacher self-improvement. Assist teachers&amp;rsquo; professional growth through AI technology.
It has collected tens of thousands of excellent teaching plans and teaching examples, established the AI Smarter School exclusive channel, and provided a teacher professional development platform for the global smart teachers to watch, discuss and communicate with the public, to promote the spread of smarter education and accelerate the teacher professional development.</description></item><item><title>Daylify</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:28:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</guid><description>Introduction Daylify is a user-friendly web application designed to help you track and record your daily moods.
Inspiration The primary motivation behind creating Daylify was to develop a practical web application that would allow users to easily track their moods. Additionally, I wanted to evaluate my personal growth and highlight the milestones of my journey.
To achieve these goals, I leveraged the power of Vue.js for the user interface and FastAPI for the API, both hosted separately.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 Vaccination Log</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 09:10:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</guid><description>On 18-Aug-2020, Taiwan finally opened its first appointment for locally-made vaccine MVC COVID-19. As this will be the very first rollout of the vaccine, there are still some doubts towards the safety of the vaccine. However, I am confident that the vaccine will be safe and effective; therefore I decided to register to receive my first dose on 23-Aug-2020.
I will keep updating this log as I receive more information before and after receiving my doses.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Copilot</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:12:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</guid><description>What is GitHub Copilot? GitHub-Copilot is basically a smart code autocomplete powered by Codex, the new AI system created by OpenAI. GitHub Copilot understands significantly more context than most code assistants. So, whether it&amp;rsquo;s in a docstring, comment, function name, or the code itself, GitHub Copilot uses the context you&amp;rsquo;ve provided and synthesizes code to match.
I received an invitation to test out GitHub Copilot during its technical preview a couple of weeks ago, and I have been using it on Visual Studio Code ever since.</description></item></channel></rss>