<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:47:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leetcode: Max Sum of a Pair With Equal Sum of Digits</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/02/leetcode-max-sum-of-a-pair-with-equal-sum-of-digits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:47:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/02/leetcode-max-sum-of-a-pair-with-equal-sum-of-digits/</guid><description>Introduction This blog post covers a solution to a Leetcode problem that requires finding the maximum sum of a pair of numbers with equal sum of digits. The task is both interesting and practical, showcasing the application of algorithm design for efficiency.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the problem, walk you through my thought process, and share the solution I came up with.
The Problem Link to question
You are given a 0-indexed array nums consisting of positive integers.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Minimum Number of Operations to Move All Balls to Each Box</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-minimum-number-of-operations-to-move-all-balls-to-each-box/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 15:58:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-minimum-number-of-operations-to-move-all-balls-to-each-box/</guid><description>Introduction This blog post covers a solution to a Leetcode problem that requires calculating the minimum number of operations needed to move all balls to each box. The task is both interesting and practical, showcasing the application of algorithm design for efficiency.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the problem, walk you through my thought process, and share the solution I came up with.
The Problem Link to question
Given a binary string boxes where boxes[i] == '1' represents a ball in the i-th box, and boxes[i] == '0' represents an empty box, calculate the minimum number of operations required to move all balls to each box.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Koko Eating Bananas</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-koko-eating-bananas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:10:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-koko-eating-bananas/</guid><description>Introduction The Koko Eating Bananas problem is an interesting challenge that involves binary search and array manipulation. The goal is to determine the minimum eating speed k such that Koko can eat all the bananas within a given number of hours h.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the problem, walk you through my thought process, and share the solution I came up with.
The Problem Link to question
You are given an array piles where piles[i] represents the number of bananas in the i-th pile.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Find the Prefix Common Array of Two Arrays</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-find-the-prefix-common-array-of-two-arrays/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 15:34:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-find-the-prefix-common-array-of-two-arrays/</guid><description>Introduction The Prefix Common Array problem is a fascinating puzzle that combines array manipulation and set operations. It requires you to find common elements in two arrays at every index and maintain a running count. While the problem may seem tricky at first, breaking it down into smaller steps reveals a very simple approach.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the problem, walk you through my thought process, and share the solution I came up with.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Construct K Palindrome Strings</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-construct-k-palindrome-strings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:19:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-construct-k-palindrome-strings/</guid><description>Introduction When I first came across the Construct K Palindrome Strings problem, I was intrigued by how it tied together two seemingly unrelated concepts: palindromes and character frequencies. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about solving a puzzle—it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the fundamental properties of strings and how they can be rearranged to meet specific constraints.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through my thought process, how I approached the problem, and the solution that I implemented.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Maximum Subarray</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:21:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</guid><description>Introduction The Maximum Subarray problem is a classic challenge in computer science and algorithm design. It provides a great exercise for understanding array manipulation, optimization techniques, and dynamic programming. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the problem statement, explore solution approaches, and analyze their efficiencies.
The Problem Link to question
Given an integer array nums, find the contiguous subarray (containing at least one number) that has the largest sum and return its sum.</description></item><item><title>Building High-Performance Application with FastAPI Redis Celery Flower Docker</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/10/building-high-performance-application-with-fastapi-redis-celery-flower-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:33:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/10/building-high-performance-application-with-fastapi-redis-celery-flower-docker/</guid><description>Introduction In the world of modern web applications, speed and scalability are critical. Sometimes, tasks like sending emails, processing reports, or running machine learning models need to be offloaded from the main API to avoid slowing down user interactions. This is where the FastAPI + Redis + Celery + Flower stack comes in—a powerful setup that enables asynchronous processing and real-time monitoring of background tasks.
This article will walk you through how these technologies work together and provide a guide for building your own high-performance backend using this stack.</description></item><item><title>Technology For Change Asia 4: Keynotes</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/03/technology-for-change-asia-4-keynotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:04:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/03/technology-for-change-asia-4-keynotes/</guid><description>Technology for Change Asia 4th featuring the founder of Wikipedia, internet entrepreneur, wiki pioneer, and technology visionary Jimmy Wales, and globally-renowned theoretical physicist, activist, futurologist, and popular science writer Michio Kaku. I had an opportunity to participate in this event for inspiring two days. Here&amp;rsquo;s the summary of each session.
Keynote interview. Building trust and creating disruption through technological innovation Description: Named a &amp;ldquo;web celeb&amp;rdquo; by Forbes, Jimmy Wales is best known as the founder of Wikipedia, a collaborative free encyclopaedia, and the Wikimedia Foundation, a charitable organisation dedicated to encouraging the growth, development and distribution of free, multilingual content.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 16:44:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</guid><description>Introduction In the bustling city of algorithms and code, even garbage collection becomes an intriguing problem. This blog post delves into the LeetCode problem titled &amp;ldquo;Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage.&amp;rdquo; The objective is to efficiently plan the collection of metal (&amp;lsquo;M&amp;rsquo;), paper (&amp;lsquo;P&amp;rsquo;), and glass (&amp;lsquo;G&amp;rsquo;) garbage spread across houses using three specialized trucks.
The Problem Link to question
You are provided with an array of strings, garbage, where each element represents the assortment of garbage at a particular house.</description></item><item><title>ORoaming by Oppo</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 16:39:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world, maintaining connectivity while traveling abroad has evolved from a luxury to a necessity. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a business traveler, a globetrotter, or someone who frequently explores new destinations, the demand for dependable and cost-effective international roaming solutions has never been more essential. Enter ORoaming.
Ordinarily, travelers need to acquire additional local or travel SIM cards, invest in Pocket WiFi devices, and explore various connectivity options to stay connected abroad.</description></item></channel></rss>