<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-science on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title>
    <link>https://nat236919.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-science on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:31:17 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nat236919.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Current Job Postings</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/11/new-york-current-job-postings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:31:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/11/new-york-current-job-postings/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a job to earn a living is challenging and time consuming, and it might not end up well as expected. Therefore, in order to effectively plan for a career, one must know which career path should be taken. This report analyses job opening positions in NY, USA with a hope that it may be useful individually and socially.
Read with Jupyter Viewer
Presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Alcohol Consumption</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/06/student-alcohol-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 08:20:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/06/student-alcohol-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Student life is messy and stressful, eventually it might lead to depression. However, we all know that cracking open a cold one with your lads always helps. In this analysis, I, for no particular reasons, would like to welcome you all to dive into Alcohol Consumption by students. Enjoy :)
Read with Jupyter Viewer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicide Rate Report (1985 to 2016)</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/04/suicide-rate-report-1985-to-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 16:43:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/posts/2019/04/suicide-rate-report-1985-to-2016/</guid>
      <description>Read with Jupyter Viewer
1. Introduction Due to a high competion in every field nowadays. We cannot deny that we must speed our pace to get ahed of others. What does it lead to? It leads to anxiety, depression, and endless tiring situations. As a consequence, suicide rates sky rocket daily and they seem to not soon decrease.
2. Objectives The main objectives of this short report are to raise the awareness of suicide rates, and provide insightful information for future research and usage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>