<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title>
    <link>https://nat236919.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 14:18:03 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nat236919.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Decorators</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2020/06/python-decorators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 14:18:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2020/06/python-decorators/</guid>
      <description>Objective In this short blog, I would like to introduce Python decorators to everyone. Some of you might have heard and used it daily. And to those who have never heard of it, let go through some demonstration to show how powerful it can be.
What a Python Decorator is TL;DR: It is a Python object that is used to modify function or class regarding its behaviour.
 Examples 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID19 API</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/06/covid19-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:39:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/06/covid19-api/</guid>
      <description>API for exploring covid-19 cases around the globe powered by FastAPI framework
Introduction As going through 2020, it is clear that the year of the Rat has NOT been friendly at all. We have experienced a series of fierce events. For instance, the tension among global giants, protesting, Australian bushfire season, extreme racial discrimination, and noticeably the COVID-19 pandemic.
COVID-19 has been spreading rapidly without showing any signs of stopping or even slowing down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monty Hall Problem</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2020/03/monty-hall-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 13:20:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2020/03/monty-hall-problem/</guid>
      <description>Source Code
What is Monty Hall Problem? The Monty Hall Problem is named for its similarity to the Let&amp;rsquo;s Make a Deal television game show hosted by Monty Hall. The problem is stated as follows. Assume that a room is equipped with three doors. Behind two are goats, and behind the third is a shiny new car. You are asked to pick a door, and will win whatever is behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Current Job Postings</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/11/new-york-current-job-postings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:31:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/11/new-york-current-job-postings/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a job to earn a living is challenging and time consuming, and it might not end up well as expected. Therefore, in order to effectively plan for a career, one must know which career path should be taken. This report analyses job opening positions in NY, USA with a hope that it may be useful individually and socially.
Read with Jupyter Viewer
Presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HABOOK Databank</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/09/habook-databank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:38:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/09/habook-databank/</guid>
      <description>HABOOK DataBank is an in-house web application that simplifies Exploratory Data Analysis for school datasets. It provides a user with the information that stakeholder need to know. It, not only, provides stakeholders with sortable tabular data, it also visualises the data to graphs (e.g., heatmaps, linecharts, scatterplots).
** NOTE: The data is altered and left out for confidentiality How it works HABOOK DataBank explores the data in the database, then performs data pre-processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Teaching Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/07/smart-teaching-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:06:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/07/smart-teaching-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>The dashboard of Teaching and Learning Bigdata Management Service allows the school team to have a general view of the use of science and technology of teachers in the whole school, and presents charts according to the time, academic year, discipline and other dimensions, which serves as an important reference for the teaching research team to plan teacher professional development plan.
Responsibility  Created a prototype version of the dashboard by analysing statistical data to determine appropriate presentations Modified MVC modules to extract data and provide an API endpoint (JSON) Validated the correctness of the queried data from the database  Find Out More https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Alcohol Consumption</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/06/student-alcohol-consumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 08:20:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/06/student-alcohol-consumption/</guid>
      <description>Student life is messy and stressful, eventually it might lead to depression. However, we all know that cracking open a cold one with your lads always helps. In this analysis, I, for no particular reasons, would like to welcome you all to dive into Alcohol Consumption by students. Enjoy :)
Read with Jupyter Viewer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicide Rate Report (1985 to 2016)</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/04/suicide-rate-report-1985-to-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 16:43:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/blog/2019/04/suicide-rate-report-1985-to-2016/</guid>
      <description>Read with Jupyter Viewer
1. Introduction Due to a high competion in every field nowadays. We cannot deny that we must speed our pace to get ahed of others. What does it lead to? It leads to anxiety, depression, and endless tiring situations. As a consequence, suicide rates sky rocket daily and they seem to not soon decrease.
2. Objectives The main objectives of this short report are to raise the awareness of suicide rates, and provide insightful information for future research and usage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>