<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handle Interactive Shell</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</guid><description>Introduction Connecting to a remote service using a python module paramiko has always been one of the well-known methods to handle such tasks. Executing commands and receiving the data from the connected server can be done quickly. The following code is a primary usage of paramiko to interact with the server.
import paramiko host = &amp;#39;127.0.0.1&amp;#39; # server host username = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; password = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; # Init SSH client client = paramiko.</description></item><item><title>Python Generators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</guid><description>Objectives In this short blog, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce Python Generators. After reading this blog, I do hope that you will understand
What Python generators are What generator function and generator expression are How to use them What are Python Generators? A special function in Python that returns a lazy iterator. It works similar to a list, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store all values in memory
Implementation So, why do we need to use generators instead of normal interators (e.</description></item><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Rock Paper Scissors Rock Paper Scissors is a game where two players simultaneously choose one of three options: rock, paper, or scissors. The player who wins the most games wins the game.
It is clear that the game is a pure chance game regarding statistics if players truly randomly choose their choices. However, it is not the case for human behaviour.
The study Social cycling and conditional responses in the Rock-Paper-Scissors game suggest that the game is not purely chance game, but rather a game that is dependent on human behaviour.</description></item><item><title>Daylify</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 09:28:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2021/11/daylify/</guid><description>Introduction Daylify is an experimental web application that allows users to record their moods on a daily basis.
Inspiration I wanted to create an easy-to-use web application to practice my skills. Furthermore, I would like to evaluate myself to see how I grow as a person, and to examine the highlights of my journey.
This project uses Vue.js for the UI, and FastAPI for the API which are hosted separately.</description></item><item><title>Introducing FastAPI</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:36:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</guid><description>Introduction Developing APIs can be painful if we don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. As I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of Python, it is my first choice for development. It has a great number of frameworks and libraries supporting web development (e.g., Django, Flask, etc.). This time I would like to introduce a super-fast and easy-to-use framework which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for a couple of years now: FastAPI.
FastAPI FastAPI is a high-performace web framework for creating APIs with Python.</description></item><item><title>Unconventional Russian Roulette</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:57:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Unconventional Russian Roulette? Unconventional Russian Roulette introduces similarities as its origin Russian Roulette. The difference is that instead of using one bullet, it uses three bullets where they are loaded adjacently.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine this scenario:
Three bullets are loaded into the cylinder adjacently, Player A has taken a shot and survived. We, as Player B, need to decide whether to take a shot or not. For the sake of simplicity, the game ends this round and here are the conditions:</description></item><item><title>Scavenger</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/11/scavenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 13:45:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/11/scavenger/</guid><description>Introduction Scavenger is an experimental web scraping project as a service that simply offers an easy-to-use functionality to scrap a website and gather a specific piece of information as needed.
Features Web Scraping: It gets its hands dirty going out to endless space of World Wide Web to make sure that you get what you need Processing: Gliding through a scraped website to seek a piece of information as required Presenting: It manages and presents the result beautifully to make it easier to comprehend Inspiration One of the core ideas on developing this project was that I wanted to create a web app application and deliver it within tight schedules.</description></item><item><title>Curiosity Jar</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/09/curiosity-jar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 15:54:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/projects/2020/09/curiosity-jar/</guid><description>Introduction This repository is a collection of data analysis projects focusing purely on expressing curiosity on a various topics ranging from science, maths, games, etc.
It generally consists three main parts:
Introduction where a concept and questions are introduced Experimental Procedures where a script is written to prove the concept Results where statistical and visual results are presented Inspiration As we have entered the information era, the Internet is full of endless information scattered all over the place.</description></item><item><title>The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 16:58:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</guid><description>Source Code Game GUI
What is The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game? The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game is a game invented by two mathematicians: Steve Humble and Yutaka Nishiyama. It is a game that seems fair at the first glance, yet has a way to increase a chance of winning significantly.
The game is based on the idea of Penney Ante game in which 2 players select their own sequential outcomes (n = 3) of a coin toss (either HEADS or TAILS).</description></item><item><title>Python Decorators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/06/python-decorators/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 14:18:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/06/python-decorators/</guid><description>Objective In this short blog, I would like to introduce Python decorators to everyone. Some of you might have heard and used it daily. And to those who have never heard of it, let go through some demonstration to show how powerful it can be.
What a Python Decorator is TL;DR: It is a Python object that is used to modify function or class regarding its behaviour.
Examples 1. Without Decorators Let&amp;rsquo;s start with vanilla functions to do some basic arithmetic operations.</description></item></channel></rss>