<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:19:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leetcode: Construct K Palindrome Strings</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-construct-k-palindrome-strings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:19:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2025/01/leetcode-construct-k-palindrome-strings/</guid><description>Introduction When I first came across the Construct K Palindrome Strings problem, I was intrigued by how it tied together two seemingly unrelated concepts: palindromes and character frequencies. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about solving a puzzle—it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the fundamental properties of strings and how they can be rearranged to meet specific constraints.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through my thought process, how I approached the problem, and the solution that I implemented.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Maximum Subarray</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:21:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/12/leetcode-maximum-subarray/</guid><description>Introduction The Maximum Subarray problem is a classic challenge in computer science and algorithm design. It provides a great exercise for understanding array manipulation, optimization techniques, and dynamic programming. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the problem statement, explore solution approaches, and analyze their efficiencies.
The Problem Link to question
Given an integer array nums, find the contiguous subarray (containing at least one number) that has the largest sum and return its sum.</description></item><item><title>Building High-Performance Application with FastAPI Redis Celery Flower Docker</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/10/building-high-performance-application-with-fastapi-redis-celery-flower-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 11:33:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/10/building-high-performance-application-with-fastapi-redis-celery-flower-docker/</guid><description>Introduction In the world of modern web applications, speed and scalability are critical. Sometimes, tasks like sending emails, processing reports, or running machine learning models need to be offloaded from the main API to avoid slowing down user interactions. This is where the FastAPI + Redis + Celery + Flower stack comes in—a powerful setup that enables asynchronous processing and real-time monitoring of background tasks.
This article will walk you through how these technologies work together and provide a guide for building your own high-performance backend using this stack.</description></item><item><title>Technology For Change Asia 4: Keynotes</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/03/technology-for-change-asia-4-keynotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:04:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2024/03/technology-for-change-asia-4-keynotes/</guid><description>Technology for Change Asia 4th featuring the founder of Wikipedia, internet entrepreneur, wiki pioneer, and technology visionary Jimmy Wales, and globally-renowned theoretical physicist, activist, futurologist, and popular science writer Michio Kaku. I had an opportunity to participate in this event for inspiring two days. Here&amp;rsquo;s the summary of each session.
Keynote interview. Building trust and creating disruption through technological innovation Description: Named a &amp;ldquo;web celeb&amp;rdquo; by Forbes, Jimmy Wales is best known as the founder of Wikipedia, a collaborative free encyclopaedia, and the Wikimedia Foundation, a charitable organisation dedicated to encouraging the growth, development and distribution of free, multilingual content.</description></item><item><title>Leetcode: Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 16:44:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/11/leetcode-minimum-amount-of-time-to-collect-garbage/</guid><description>Introduction In the bustling city of algorithms and code, even garbage collection becomes an intriguing problem. This blog post delves into the LeetCode problem titled &amp;ldquo;Minimum Amount of Time to Collect Garbage.&amp;rdquo; The objective is to efficiently plan the collection of metal (&amp;lsquo;M&amp;rsquo;), paper (&amp;lsquo;P&amp;rsquo;), and glass (&amp;lsquo;G&amp;rsquo;) garbage spread across houses using three specialized trucks.
The Problem Link to question
You are provided with an array of strings, garbage, where each element represents the assortment of garbage at a particular house.</description></item><item><title>ORoaming by Oppo</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 16:39:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/10/oroaming-by-oppo/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world, maintaining connectivity while traveling abroad has evolved from a luxury to a necessity. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a business traveler, a globetrotter, or someone who frequently explores new destinations, the demand for dependable and cost-effective international roaming solutions has never been more essential. Enter ORoaming.
Ordinarily, travelers need to acquire additional local or travel SIM cards, invest in Pocket WiFi devices, and explore various connectivity options to stay connected abroad.</description></item><item><title>Farewell Book Depository</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/05/farewell-book-depository/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 14:54:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/05/farewell-book-depository/</guid><description>Book Depository, once a prominent online book seller based in the UK, captured the hearts of book lovers around the world. Renowned for its vast collection of affordably-priced books and its unique offering of free worldwide shipping, Book Depository served as a haven for readers seeking diverse literary treasures. Particularly for individuals residing in third world countries, where foreign language books often come with exorbitant price tags, Book Depository provided an invaluable platform for access to knowledge and imagination.</description></item><item><title>Engineering to Consulting</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/04/engineering-to-consulting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2023/04/engineering-to-consulting/</guid><description>In 2022, I faced a career crossroads when I received an offer to become a consultant in a private tech firm. While excited about the opportunity to try something new, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel apprehensive about leaving behind my comfortable role as a software engineer. Ultimately, I took a leap of faith and accepted the offer, eager to see where this new path would take me.
However, my excitement quickly turned to reality when I realized that being a consultant requires a different skill set than what I had previously honed as an engineer.</description></item><item><title>Handle Interactive Shell</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 09:50:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/10/handle-interactive-shell/</guid><description>Introduction Connecting to a remote service using a python module paramiko has always been one of the well-known methods to handle such tasks. Executing commands and receiving the data from the connected server can be done quickly. The following code is a primary usage of paramiko to interact with the server.
import paramiko host = &amp;#39;127.0.0.1&amp;#39; # server host username = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; password = &amp;#39;root&amp;#39; # Init SSH client client = paramiko.</description></item><item><title>Python Generators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</guid><description>Objectives In this short blog, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce Python Generators. After reading this blog, I do hope that you will understand
What Python generators are What generator function and generator expression are How to use them What are Python Generators? A special function in Python that returns a lazy iterator. It works similar to a list, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store all values in memory
Implementation So, why do we need to use generators instead of normal interators (e.</description></item></channel></rss>