<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python Generators</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 11:58:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/05/python-generators/</guid><description>Objectives In this short blog, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce Python Generators. After reading this blog, I do hope that you will understand
What Python generators are What generator function and generator expression are How to use them What are Python Generators? A special function in Python that returns a lazy iterator. It works similar to a list, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store all values in memory
Implementation So, why do we need to use generators instead of normal interators (e.</description></item><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Rock Paper Scissors Rock Paper Scissors is a game where two players simultaneously choose one of three options: rock, paper, or scissors. The player who wins the most games wins the game.
It is clear that the game is a pure chance game regarding statistics if players truly randomly choose their choices. However, it is not the case for human behaviour.
The study Social cycling and conditional responses in the Rock-Paper-Scissors game suggest that the game is not purely chance game, but rather a game that is dependent on human behaviour.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 Vaccination Log</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 09:10:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/covid-19-vaccination-log/</guid><description>On 18-Aug-2020, Taiwan finally opened its first appointment for locally-made vaccine MVC COVID-19. As this will be the very first rollout of the vaccine, there are still some doubts towards the safety of the vaccine. However, I am confident that the vaccine will be safe and effective; therefore I decided to register to receive my first dose on 23-Aug-2020.
I will keep updating this log as I receive more information before and after receiving my doses.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Copilot</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 17:12:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/08/github-copilot/</guid><description>What is GitHub Copilot? GitHub-Copilot is basically a smart code autocomplete powered by Codex, the new AI system created by OpenAI. GitHub Copilot understands significantly more context than most code assistants. So, whether it&amp;rsquo;s in a docstring, comment, function name, or the code itself, GitHub Copilot uses the context you&amp;rsquo;ve provided and synthesizes code to match.
I received an invitation to test out GitHub Copilot during its technical preview a couple of weeks ago, and I have been using it on Visual Studio Code ever since.</description></item><item><title>Introducing FastAPI</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:36:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2021/06/introducing-fastapi/</guid><description>Introduction Developing APIs can be painful if we don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. As I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fan of Python, it is my first choice for development. It has a great number of frameworks and libraries supporting web development (e.g., Django, Flask, etc.). This time I would like to introduce a super-fast and easy-to-use framework which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for a couple of years now: FastAPI.
FastAPI FastAPI is a high-performace web framework for creating APIs with Python.</description></item><item><title>Unconventional Russian Roulette</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:57:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Unconventional Russian Roulette? Unconventional Russian Roulette introduces similarities as its origin Russian Roulette. The difference is that instead of using one bullet, it uses three bullets where they are loaded adjacently.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine this scenario:
Three bullets are loaded into the cylinder adjacently, Player A has taken a shot and survived. We, as Player B, need to decide whether to take a shot or not. For the sake of simplicity, the game ends this round and here are the conditions:</description></item><item><title>The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 16:58:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</guid><description>Source Code Game GUI
What is The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game? The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game is a game invented by two mathematicians: Steve Humble and Yutaka Nishiyama. It is a game that seems fair at the first glance, yet has a way to increase a chance of winning significantly.
The game is based on the idea of Penney Ante game in which 2 players select their own sequential outcomes (n = 3) of a coin toss (either HEADS or TAILS).</description></item><item><title>When Null is An Object</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/when-null-is-an-object/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 09:50:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/when-null-is-an-object/</guid><description>JavaScript is weird; that is all I can say about it. If I were asked to compare JS with an animal, it would definitely be a cat. Despite its overloaded cuteness, it always seems that it is plotting against you. However, at the end of the day, we still love them.
The fun started when I was working on a function that returns an object. The object was meant to be used for displaying data on a webpage.</description></item><item><title>Video Autoplay and Time Skipping</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/08/video-autoplay-and-time-skipping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 09:30:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/08/video-autoplay-and-time-skipping/</guid><description>Recently, I have been tasked to maintain one of the projects that provide a video player service powered by a powerful library videojs which claims to be the most popular open-source HTML5 player framework, according to its site.
The previous engineers working before me had contributed a tremendous work by creating a customised version of our own player which provides functionalities, such as time markers, etc. It worked perfectly. Until I was asked to implement three new functionalities onto the video player:</description></item><item><title>Sun Moon Lake e-Passes</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/08/sun-moon-lake-e-passes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 21:07:36 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/08/sun-moon-lake-e-passes/</guid><description>Sun Moon Lake is one of the most famous attractions where most tourists who are in Taichung want to visit. Travelling there, of course, is well-known to be time-consuming; moreover, it can be costly. Therefore, several travelling packages are available for purchase at the HSR, TRA, Nantou Bus station, etc. which help save a lot of money. Generally, we would get paper tickets after purchasing.
Recently, in order to match up with an increasing number of mobile usage, The Nantou government has introduced e-Passes which can be purchased online.</description></item></channel></rss>