<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title>
    <link>https://nat236919.github.io/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 15:54:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nat236919.github.io/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Curiosity Jar</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/09/curiosity-jar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 15:54:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/09/curiosity-jar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This repository is a collection of data analysis projects focusing purely on expressing curiosity on a various topics ranging from science, maths, games, etc.
It generally consists three main parts:
 Introduction where a concept and questions are introduced Experimental Procedures where a script is written to prove the concept Results where statistical and visual results are presented  All Projects Link to GitHub Repository
 The Monty Hall problem The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID19 API</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/06/covid19-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:39:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2020/06/covid19-api/</guid>
      <description>API for exploring covid-19 cases around the globe powered by FastAPI framework
Introduction As going through 2020, it is clear that the year of the Rat has NOT been friendly at all. We have experienced a series of fierce events. For instance, the tension among global giants, protesting, Australian bushfire season, extreme racial discrimination, and noticeably the COVID-19 pandemic.
COVID-19 has been spreading rapidly without showing any signs of stopping or even slowing down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HABOOK Databank</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/09/habook-databank/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:38:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/09/habook-databank/</guid>
      <description>HABOOK DataBank is an in-house web application that simplifies Exploratory Data Analysis for school datasets. It provides a user with the information that stakeholder need to know. It, not only, provides stakeholders with sortable tabular data, it also visualises the data to graphs (e.g., heatmaps, linecharts, scatterplots).
** NOTE: The data is altered and left out for confidentialityHow it works HABOOK DataBank explores the data in the database, then performs data pre-processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Teaching Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/07/smart-teaching-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:06:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nat236919.github.io/projects/2019/07/smart-teaching-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>The dashboard of Teaching and Learning Bigdata Management Service allows the school team to have a general view of the use of science and technology of teachers in the whole school, and presents charts according to the time, academic year, discipline and other dimensions, which serves as an important reference for the teaching research team to plan teacher professional development plan.
Responsibility  Created a prototype version of the dashboard by analysing statistical data to determine appropriate presentations Modified MVC modules to extract data and provide an API endpoint (JSON) Validated the correctness of the queried data from the database  Find Out More https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>