<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>curiosity-jar on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/tags/curiosity-jar/</link><description>Recent content in curiosity-jar on Nuttaphat Arunoprayoch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuttaphat.com/tags/curiosity-jar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rock Paper Scissors</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:15:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2022/02/rock-paper-scissors/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Rock Paper Scissors Rock Paper Scissors is a game where two players simultaneously choose one of three options: rock, paper, or scissors. The player who wins the most games wins the game.
It is clear that the game is a pure chance game regarding statistics if players truly randomly choose their choices. However, it is not the case for human behaviour.
The study Social cycling and conditional responses in the Rock-Paper-Scissors game suggest that the game is not purely chance game, but rather a game that is dependent on human behaviour.</description></item><item><title>Unconventional Russian Roulette</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:57:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/11/unconventional-russian-roulette/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Unconventional Russian Roulette? Unconventional Russian Roulette introduces similarities as its origin Russian Roulette. The difference is that instead of using one bullet, it uses three bullets where they are loaded adjacently.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine this scenario:
Three bullets are loaded into the cylinder adjacently, Player A has taken a shot and survived. We, as Player B, need to decide whether to take a shot or not. For the sake of simplicity, the game ends this round and here are the conditions:</description></item><item><title>The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 16:58:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/09/the-humble-nishiyama-randomness-game/</guid><description>Source Code Game GUI
What is The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game? The Humble-Nishiyama Randomness Game is a game invented by two mathematicians: Steve Humble and Yutaka Nishiyama. It is a game that seems fair at the first glance, yet has a way to increase a chance of winning significantly.
The game is based on the idea of Penney Ante game in which 2 players select their own sequential outcomes (n = 3) of a coin toss (either HEADS or TAILS).</description></item><item><title>Monty Hall Problem</title><link>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/03/monty-hall-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 13:20:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nuttaphat.com/posts/2020/03/monty-hall-problem/</guid><description>Source Code
What is Monty Hall Problem The Monty Hall Problem is named for its similarity to the Let&amp;rsquo;s Make a Deal television game show hosted by Monty Hall. The problem is stated as follows. Assume that a room is equipped with three doors. Behind two are goats, and behind the third is a shiny new car. You are asked to pick a door, and will win whatever is behind it.</description></item></channel></rss>